{
    "id": "d4f4f1641ccc4b4682d934fa9ed83d36",
    "title": "Future Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "1f952b7d8961474db01a72da27d61d98",
            "title": "Future Tense",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "We ……………………….. Rome in January.",
                    "description": "We use the present continuous to talk about future events that have already been planned.",
                    "answers": [
                        "visit",
                        "are visiting",
                        "will visit"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "John and Alice ………………………… in May.",
                    "description": "We use the present continuous to talk about future events that have already been planned.",
                    "answers": [
                        "get married",
                        "are getting married",
                        "will get married"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………………. probably be home late tonight.",
                    "description": "We use the simple future to talk about future events which are not already decided.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will",
                        "am going to",
                        "am"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I think our party ………………………. the election.",
                    "description": "We use the simple future to talk about future events which are not already decided.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will win",
                        "would win",
                        "is going to win"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………… I help you?",
                    "description": "\r\nWe can use shall to ask whether someone wants us to do something. Will is not possible with this meaning.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Will",
                        "Shall",
                        "Would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "……………………….. you help me?",
                    "description": "We use will in requests for help. Shall is not possible with this meaning.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Will",
                        "Shall",
                        "Should"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ……………………….. kill you if you read my letters again.",
                    "description": "Will is used in threats.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will",
                        "must",
                        "would"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "By next year we ……………………………… in America for ten years.",
                    "description": "We use the future perfect to say that something will be finished or completed by a certain time in the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will be living",
                        "will have lived",
                        "will live"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will think of you when I ……………………….. on the beach next week.",
                    "description": "When the main clause is in the future tense, we often use present tenses in the subordinate clauses to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will be lying",
                        "am lying",
                        "will have been lying"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I will give all that I ………………………..",
                    "description": "\r\nWhen the main clause is in the future tense, we often use present tenses in the subordinate clauses to refer to the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have",
                        "had",
                        "will have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Don’t call them now – they …………………………. dinner.",
                    "description": "We often use will to make predictions about the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have",
                        "will have",
                        "will be having"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "By next Christmas I …………………………….. here for ten years.",
                    "description": "The future perfect puts emphasis on completion and the future perfect continuous tense puts emphasis on the idea of continuity.\r\nThese tense forms are used to talk about actions and situations that are currently unfinished but will be finished by a certain point of time in the future.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will work",
                        "will have worked",
                        "will have been working"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}